Academic Planning Services fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- External review files, 1972 - 1999; F-202-2; 1.89 m of textual records
  - School of Engineering Science external review files, 1993 - 1996; F-202-2-27; 5 cm of textual records
    School of Engineering Science
    - Engineering Science external review, vol. 1, 1993 - 1996; F-202-2-27-0-1 (Archival box - standard 202-16)
    - Engineering Science external review, vol. 2, 1993 - 1996; F-202-2-27-0-2 (Archival box - standard 202-16)
  - Department of Sociology and Anthropology external review files, 1993 - 1999; F-202-2-28; 8 cm of textual records
    Department of Sociology and Anthropology
    - Sociology and Anthropology external review, vol. 1, 1993 - 1999; F-202-2-28-0-1 (Archival box - standard 202-16)
    - Sociology and Anthropology external review, vol. 2, 1993 - 1999; F-202-2-28-0-2 (Archival box - standard 202-16)
    - Sociology and Anthropology external review, vol. 3, 1993 - 1999; F-202-2-28-0-3 (Archival box - standard 202-16)
  - Department of Women's Studies external review files, 1994 - 1995; F-202-2-29; 3 cm of textual records
    Department of Gender, Sexuality, and Women's Studies
    - Women's Studies external review, vol. 1, 1994 - 1995; F-202-2-29-0-1 (Archival box - standard 202-17)
    - Women's Studies external review, vol. 2, 1994 - 1995; F-202-2-29-0-2 (Archival box - standard 202-17)
  - School of Criminology external review files, 1994 - 1996; F-202-2-30; 4 cm of textual records
    School of Criminology
    - Criminology external review, vol. 1, 1994 - 1996; F-202-2-30-0-1 (Archival box - standard 202-17)
    - Criminology external review, vol. 2, 1994 - 1996; F-202-2-30-0-2 (Archival box - standard 202-17)
    - Criminology external review, vol. 3, 1994 - 1996; F-202-2-30-0-3 (Archival box - standard 202-17)
  - School of Resource and Environmental Management external review files, 1994 - 1997; F-202-2-31; 3 cm of textual records
    School of Resource and Environmental Management
    - Resource and Environmental Management external review, vol. 1, 1994 - 1997; F-202-2-31-0-1 (Archival box - standard 202-17)
    - Resource and Environmental Management external review, vol. 2, 1994 - 1997; F-202-2-31-0-2 (Archival box - standard 202-17)
  - School of Contemporary Arts external review files, 1995 - 1998; F-202-2-32; 3 cm of textual records
    School for the Contemporary Arts
    - Contemporary Arts external review, vol. 1, 1995 - 1998; F-202-2-32-0-1 (Archival box - standard 202-17)
    - Contemporary Arts external review, vol. 2, 1995 - 1998; F-202-2-32-0-2 (Archival box - standard 202-17)
  - Cooperative Education external review files, 1996; F-202-2-33; 2 cm of textual records
    Cooperative Education
    - Cooperative Education external review, 1996; F-202-2-33-0-1 (Archival box - small 202-20)
- TRIUMF correspondence files, 1981 - 1986; F-202-3; 25 cm of textual records; TRIUMF
  TRIUMF is Canada's national laboratory for particle and nuclear physics, operated as a joint venture by a consortium of universities. Its facilities support both pure and applied research and include the particle accelerator (cyclotron) and the Isotope Separation and ACceleration (ISAC) facility.
  The idea of building a cyclotron in western Canada was first conceived by Dr. J.R. Richardson on Galiano Island in 1962. Simon Fraser University, the University of British Columbia and the University of Victoria collaborated on a proposal in 1966 for the Tri-University Meson Facility (TRIUMF). The University of Alberta joined the group and TRIUMF was formally established by the four universities in 1968 with funding from the Atomic Energy Control Board (AECB).
  The early years of TRIUMF were primarily concerned with the planning, design and construction of the facility on the campus of UBC, and on February 9, 1976 it was officially opened by the Prime Minister of Canda, Pierre Trudeau. In the same year the four founding universities signed a Letter of Agreement with the National Research Council of Canada (NRC), to provide on-going core operational funding. The organization was formally constituted as a Joint Venture between the four universities in November 1981. A number of other Canadian universities are affiliated with TRIUMF as Associate Members, while Carleton University and the University of Toronto became Joint Venture members around 2003-2004. Although owned by the consortium, TRIUMF has always made its facilities available to other Canadian and foreign researchers.
  TRIUMF is governed by a Board of Management which comprises individuals drawn from its Joint Venture and Associate Member universities and which is responsible for policy, budget, and fund-raising. TRIUMF is administered by a Director, assisted by a number of Advisory Committees, whose number and composition has varied over the years. The organization is internally structured into a number of divisions which have also changed over time through periodic reorganizations.
  This series consists of files created by SFU faculty and administrators who served as SFU representatives on the TRIUMF Board of Management in the first half of the 1980s. The material (some of it originally housed in binders) appears to have been transferred at some point in the early 1990s to Academic Planning Services and consolidated into a single block. Activities and topics documented in the files include planning for the construction of a KAON factory, contribution funding, negotiation of a borrowing agreement, IT planning, patent policy, employee relations, the review of TRIUMF by the NRC (1983), the internal review of the Operations Committee (1984-1985), and TRIUMF's 10th anniversary celebrations in 1985. Records include correspondence, reports, meeting summaries, agreements, legal advice, notes and working papers, and TRIUMF newsletters and other printed matter.
  TRIUMF
  For other records relating to TRIUMF, see two series in the fonds of the Office of the Vice-President, Academic (F-200):
  F-200-3-3-8, Faculty correspondence. Faculty of Science. TRIUMF (1973-1992).
  F-200-8-6-9, Committees. External committees and bodies. TRIUMF (1989-1990).
  See also some files in the President's Office fonds (F-193):
  F-193-31-2, Universities and colleges. Joint university projects (1964-1996).
  A file list list is available.
  - General correspondence, vol. 1, 1981 - 1983; F-202-3-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 202-18)
  - General correspondence, vol. 2, 1981 - 1983; F-202-3-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 202-18)
  - Notes / working papers, 1982 - 1983; F-202-3-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 202-18)
  - Report to the NRC Review Committee on TRIUMF, vol. 1, April 1983; F-202-3-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 202-18)
  - Report to the NRC Review Committee on TRIUMF, vol. 2, April 1983; F-202-3-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 202-18)
  - General correspondence, 1983 - 1984; F-202-3-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 202-18)
  - TRIUMF - correspondence, 1983 - 1984; F-202-3-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 202-18)
  - Borrowing agreement, 1983 - 1985; F-202-3-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 202-18)
  - Litigation case, 1983 - 1985; F-202-3-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 202-18)
  - Management Information System project, 1984; F-202-3-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 202-19)
  - Report: A New Classification System for TRIUMF Employees, 1984; F-202-3-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 202-19)
  - Site development proposal, 1984; F-202-3-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 202-19)
  - Correspondence, 1984 - 1985; F-202-3-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 202-19)
  - Operations Committee review, 1984 - 1985; F-202-3-0-0-14 (Archival box - standard 202-19)
  - TRIUMF patent policy, 1984 - 1985; F-202-3-0-0-15 (Archival box - standard 202-19)
  - SFU TRIUMF group, 1984 - 1985; F-202-3-0-0-16 (Archival box - standard 202-19)
  - Reports to Advisory Board on TRIUMF re: NRC constitution, 1985; F-202-3-0-0-17 (Archival box - standard 202-19)
  - Tenth anniversary celebration, 1985; F-202-3-0-0-18 (Archival box - standard 202-19)
  - TRIUMF proposal for a KAON factory, vol. 1, 1985 - 1986; F-202-3-0-0-19 (Archival box - standard 202-19)
  - TRIUMF proposal for a KAON factory, vol. 2, 1985 - 1986; F-202-3-0-0-20 (Archival box - standard 202-19)
- General correspondence files, 1985 - 1992; F-202-4; 11 cm of textual records
  Series consists of general correspondence files created or inherited by Academic Planning Services. Activities and topics documented include proposals for a PhD program in Engineering Science and an MA program in aquaculture, and a proposal considered in 1991-1992 to establish an SFU branch campus in Oita prefecture in Japan. Records include correspondence, proposals, curriculum descriptions, budgets, and brochures and other printed matter.
  Further accruals to the series may occur, but are not expected.
  - PhD in Engineering Science, 1985 - 1990; F-202-4-0-0-1 (Archival box - small 202-20)
  - Master of Acquaculture program, 1989 - 1991; F-202-4-0-0-2 (Archival box - small 202-20)
  - Japan campus, vol. 1, 1991 - 1992; F-202-4-0-0-3 (Archival box - small 202-20)
  - Japan campus, vol. 2, 1991 - 1992; F-202-4-0-0-4 (Archival box - small 202-21)
  - Japan campus, vol. 3, 1991 - 1992; F-202-4-0-0-5 (Archival box - small 202-21)